let's look at the solution to our flat
page table size quiz we are asked what
the total size of the page tables in the
system is there are two processes in the
system so there will be two page tables
we need to add up their sizes the page
size is 4 kiloby the applications have a
32-bit virtual address space so we have
two processes times 2 to the 32nd bytes
of address space divided by 2 to the 12
bytes in a page this is how many p Pages
we have times the size of an entry is 8
bytes which gives us 2 * 8 is 16 * 2 to
the 20th 2 to the 20th bytes is a
megabyte so we have 16 mbes note that it
didn't matter how much memory the
processes are actually using the flat
page table needs to have an entry for
every possible page in the virtual
address space not only for the pages we
are actually using also it doesn't
matter how much physical memory we
actually have what matters is what the
size of the entry is so for example this
entry was designed to accommodate up to
a 64-bit physical address even though
the system actually has much less memory
why would you do this well because you
want to build a system such that it can
expand its memory if necessary for
example by adding more memory modules